<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-12-26T22:34:48-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//</id><title type="html">Stephen Knott</title><subtitle>Stephen Knott UI Designer / Front-end Developer
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">A logo built with love.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/design/logo/2016/11/09/a-logo-built-with-love.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A logo built with love." /><published>2016-11-09T11:32:06-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-09T11:32:06-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/design/logo/2016/11/09/a-logo-built-with-love</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/design/logo/2016/11/09/a-logo-built-with-love.html">&lt;p&gt;I remember once when Jim from Ace Ticket pulled me into his office. We started talking about Ace’s logo and he was interested in a redesign. As he started to get into the reasons why he wanted to do a redesign, I stopped him as soon as I could and said there was no reason for it. I truly felt that the natural evolution of Ace’s logo was a classic design that may just need some tweaking here and there, but there was no need for an overhaul. There was something special about that logo Jim had paid some “design guy” a couple of bucks to create for him, and I strongly believed that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-image-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/20161108/ace-ticket-evolution.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;The evolution of Ace's logo&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After talking Jim down from the idea of a redesign, he asked me to create something for Ace’s charity, Ace Embrace. I ran through many ideas that week as to what this logo could be. Since most of the charities Jim had donated to at that point were geared towards children, I went down a rabbit hole of silhouettes and crayon typefaces, trying to create something that represented Ace and showed compassion for children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the day came when I had to present the logos and I felt like all the ideas so far fell flat. There was nothing that I could be proud of and with little time left before the big meeting, the only thing I was sure of was that Jim probably wouldn’t like any of them either. Now, I can’t recall how long I stared at those logos, debating which one I was going to show Jim first, but I remember how I felt when the idea hit me. It was those arches in the Ace logo, that top curve in the ticket that always attracted my eye; it was love every time I looked at it. I started to wonder if I could somehow arrange into a heart. After only a few minutes of playing around, it all just came together. It was that ‘Ah-ha!’ moment, that feeling designers love when they feel they’ve nailed the solution of their design problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-image-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/20161108/heart-logo.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;Love at first sight.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The heart had it all. It gleamed with Ace’s personality and showed the caring side that Jim had for so many charities that people don’t often get to see. After some additional changes in color, it now came time to find a typeface for Ace Embrace. With past iterations using a more clownish typeface and knowing that in the sports industry slab typefaces are often the norm, I wanted Ace Embrace to have a more sophisticated look, something that emoted an angelic feeling when looked at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the concave curve in Calson’s A that once again had me in love. When I brought the two together, the way the curve of the ticket rolled into the curves of the heart, I felt no need to go further with testing other typefaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-image-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/20161108/A.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;That curve, ooh-lala.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, the project finally felt whole and I was satisfied in creating a solid logo to present to Jim. So I once again gathered all my mocks, but this time I was able to hold my head up high knowing that when we discussed the future of the Ace Embrace logo, we now had a solid option to go with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-image-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/20161108/hero-ace-embrace.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:100%&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;subtext&quot;&gt;The final design.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><summary type="html">I remember once when Jim from Ace Ticket pulled me into his office. We started talking about Ace’s logo and he was interested in a redesign. As he started to get into the reasons why he wanted to do a redesign, I stopped him as soon as I could and said there was no reason for it. I truly felt that the natural evolution of Ace’s logo was a classic design that may just need some tweaking here and there, but there was no need for an overhaul. There was something special about that logo Jim had paid some “design guy” a couple of bucks to create for him, and I strongly believed that.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out with the old, create something new.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/art/2016/11/04/out-with-the-old-create-something-new.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out with the old, create something new." /><published>2016-11-04T08:47:01-04:00</published><updated>2016-11-04T08:47:01-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/art/2016/11/04/out-with-the-old-create-something-new</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/art/2016/11/04/out-with-the-old-create-something-new.html">&lt;p&gt;A portfolio website is every designer’s dream project, which can sometimes turn into an endless pursuit of perfection. An opportunity to showcase yourself, reveal your talents, woo the crowd. But are you ever satisfied with the end results? With the medium being so fluid, can there ever be a real final product?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember what it was like to build my first portfolio website back in 2006. Fullscreen Flash websites were all the rage and I was determined to learn everything I could about it what it would take to build my own. With all the sounds and all the movement I could figure out, I wanted to show any user that came across the website that I was cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved building that Flash website. It brought great attention to my skills in Flash, but maintaining it was atrocious. As my portfolio grew, I dreaded going in to update it, so when I was living in Santa Rosa I decided it was time for a new update. This time I wanted to play on words with my last name, leading me to knottyouraveragedesigner.com. Whew, what a tongue twister!  Yet I loved it and felt that it worked with my personality as a designer. Confident, clever, with a wink and a nod to my goofy side. My theme was tying ideas together using rope knots to bring each panel together. With the creative side decided, I knew the problem I really wanted to tackle: how was I going to maintain it in the future? Turns out the answer was HTML, CSS, and KISS (Keep It Simple, Stupid).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, I have been able to shrink my domain down to knottaverage.com. The name still shows a proud designer yet a little wiser with age, using new technologies in a more responsible fashion but still chasing the carrot in an endless pursuit to create perfection.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">A portfolio website is every designer’s dream project, which can sometimes turn into an endless pursuit of perfection. An opportunity to showcase yourself, reveal your talents, woo the crowd. But are you ever satisfied with the end results? With the medium being so fluid, can there ever be a real final product?</summary></entry></feed>
